[ Watch on kissFlix.co ]
[Spring of The Blade]
[Episode 6]
You want revenge.
Do you think those few
martial wanderers alone
can help you?
In this grave called the Xie family,
the living suffer more than the dead.
I'm the only one
who can help you.
Is Your Lordship willing to help me?
I used to just
want you to be obedient,
but I realized you're not one
to submit easily.
So I figured
I should change my strategy.
Let's form an alliance.
♪ Sorrowed by many a farewell,
comforted by sweet memories ♪
Through thick and thin.
♪ One life, one love,
one heart devoted to you ♪
I mean, to protect and support each other.
Are you in?
♪ In the depths of darkness,
you are the stars ♪
♪ Trample the abyss, together we run ♪
♪ May we grow deep in years together,
sharing one life and one pillow ♪
I have plenty of patience.
♪ Rise and fall as one,
whether we're united or apart ♪
You will figure it out.
♪ Hand in hand,
we brave all the storms of life ♪
♪ Never to part, forevermore ♪
Mother.
Since you returned to the residence,
we haven't talked much.
You call me Mother,
but I've not fulfilled my motherly duty,
failing to protect you.
I'm so ashamed.
Old Madam
wanted to have a good talk with you
after you returned.
But she's getting on in years
and hasn't been feeling well lately,
so she asked me to talk to you.
That night,
when you were injured,
she was
deeply distressed.
I'm taking her away to protect her.
Any objections?
If she was distressed,
why did she give me to Lord Yan?
You've been away for long,
so naturally, you don't know
the rules of the inner quarters.
With Concubine Mei now calling the shots
both inside and out
and Nanny Rong emboldened by her backing,
do you realize the predicament
Old Madam is in?
In all matters,
when the master speaks,
servants shouldn't question it.
When the husband speaks,
the wife shouldn't question it.
When the elders speak,
juniors shouldn't question it.
Do you understand?
Yes.
I will keep in mind
what you just said.
I had this wound medicine
specially prepared
for you.
Apply it for Fourth Lady
after you go back.
Yes.
Also,
Old Madam
fined Nanny Rong three months' wages.
That should
right some wrongs for you.
So my body full of wounds
and nearly losing my life
amount to
nothing more than
3 months of someone's wages.
Thank you, Mother.
I'll take my leave now
so as not to disturb your rest.
Qingyuan.
These days,
rumors about you and Lord Yan
are everywhere.
Old Madam wants you to
stay in the residence
and not go out until the rumors die down,
to avoid further gossip.
Noted.
That girl...
It's a shame
she looks too much like you.
Go ahead and speak.
Second Madam,
if only you saw it.
In broad daylight,
that girl was
with that man Yan,
tugging at each other
and flirting.
Talk about shameless!
As they say,
the apple doesn't fall far from the tree.
A crooked stick will
always have a crooked shadow.
The rich and powerful in Hengtang
all want to cling to
that corrupt official for protection.
Keeping Qingyuan in our residence
has its uses.
Second Madam,
what brilliant foresight!
You're so wise.
No wonder you're in charge.
Through and through,
the Xie family still has to rely on you.
Is that a new bracelet?
Looks quite heavy.
You have a good eye.
It's just coated with gold dust,
not worth much.
You manage the Xie Estate.
So many eyes are on you.
At your age,
I shouldn't have to teach you
not to flaunt your wealth.
Are you dying for others to see
your little illicit gain?
Second Madam,
I have no other intentions.
I just want to
handle things well for you.
Alright.
I'm not blaming you.
If I don't feed my underlings well,
that little silver
won't come into my pocket either.
In my eyes,
this thing of yours
isn't really a big deal.
I just hope it doesn't set off suspicion
and lead people to discover
the dealings behind the estate.
The consequences will be too heavy to bear
even with the two of us combined.
You're absolutely right.
I'm aware of the gravity of the situation.
[Danyue Pavilion]
My Lady,
you really hit the nail on the head.
I probed into it.
Nanny Rong is
indeed a dog serving multiple masters.
Every night after she gets off work,
she goes to Liuhua Courtyard
to tip them off.
She and Mei Yinghua must be
up to something shady in the estate.
No one wakes up early for no reason.
Overseeing such a lucrative estate,
they must have
skimmed a hefty profit for themselves.
Exactly.
She bought a gold bracelet days ago,
and couldn't stop showing it off.
I wonder how much hard-earned money
she's extorted from the tenants.
With Mei Yinghua backing her
and Old Madam giving her free rein,
it's no wonder a nanny like her
is lawless in the Xie household.
She goes around bullying the weak,
shortchanges the tenant farmers,
and runs amok in the residence.
To bring her down,
you have to dismantle her backing
and leave her completely on her own.
You're right, My Lady.
Baoxian.
Do something for me.
Greetings, Lord Yan!
Well,
Lord Yan,
we're all busy with governmental affairs.
May I ask what this meeting
is about?
Well, i-it's not really the time
to be painting the town red.
I was afraid
that you lords are too busy,
so I invited you to revisit this place.
Perhaps you might recall something.
The murderer who assassinated
the Xie Estate manager
also came here to drink with courtesans
before he died.
I wonder
who he came here with that night.
Was it you?
No, no.
It wasn't me.
Or you?
N-No, My Lord.
I truly have no clue about it.
That shouldn't be.
Only a handful of
Zuixian Tavern flower tokens
exist in all of Hengtang.
How did it end up on the murderer?
Lord Guo, I remember you have one.
Take it out and let us see.
Lord Yan,
you must be joking.
How could I have such a token?
Right.
I was just joking.
Why's everyone so nervous?
Sit, sit.
-Come on. Please.
-Lord Guo, please.
-Sit, sit.
-Sure.
However,
it seems the estate manager
lost a ledger before he died.
Lord Guo, do you think
the ledger was hidden by the killer,
or
did it really fall into the river?
Lord Yan,
how... would I know?
Perhaps it really fell into the river.
Fell into the river.
It fell into the river.
Right, right.
Speaking of the ledger,
I've heard a story.
In a certain estate,
the dividends meant for the tenant farmers
were repeatedly deducted.
This left the tenants with no choice
but to borrow money from the government.
Money is easy to borrow
but hard to repay.
The compound interest accumulates quickly.
So the people
could only use their food at home
as collateral.
As time passed,
the food ran out,
and they couldn't repay the money.
Take a guess, Your Lordships.
Where did the money
they borrowed come from?
I have no clue.
-Me neither.
I think the real kicker
of this story is that
the borrowed money is exactly
the money taken from the tenants' pockets
in the first place.
Interesting, isn't it?
Yes, yes!
Yes! S-So very interesting.
Interesting.
They say the ledger fell into the river.
Do you believe it?
I don't believe it anyway.
Neither do I.
But Your Lordship,
the ledger hasn't been found yet.
Won't doing this
alert the enemy?
That's exactly why
we have to alert the enemy.
Keep a close eye on them these few days.
They'll definitely lose their composure
and reveal something useful to us.
-Yes.
Has Fourth Lady been here recently?
No word from her yet.
[Chuxiang Pavilion]
-Guo.
-Second Young Master!
Come, come.
Why did you start drinking by yourself?
Come on, join me.
Why didn't you get a lady
to sing a tune or two?
Let's drink.
Guo,
what's wrong?
Seems like you have a lot on your mind.
Did something go wrong with our business?
It's fine.
Second Young Master.
I heard that
Lord Yan has been getting
quite close to your family of late.
Have you heard anything about it?
Of course I have!
You know what?
Lord Yan's taken a fancy
to my fourth sister.
They're really a match made in heaven.
-A handsome couple.
-Yeah, okay.
A perfect match.
What I really want to ask is
about the treasure
I asked you to keep for me before.
Have you been keeping it safe?
Treasure?
What treasure?
Oh, you mean those picture books.
Yes, yes.
I'm really sorry about them.
My mother found them and confiscated them.
Confiscated?
-I didn't know how to tell you—
-W-What about the box?
What box?
The wooden box that held the books.
There's an ink seal of
Jinsu Pastry Shop on it.
Did she take that too?
Second Young Master,
didn't I tell you
to keep it safe for me
and not to give it to anyone else?
-But my mother isn't just anyone else.
-You...
What's wrong, Guo?
Why so nervous?
Is that box so valuable?
Relax.
How about this?
When I go back,
I'll ask her about it.
You must ask her. Please.
You have to.
Come. Let's drink.
Mother!
Mother,
where did I put my wooden box?
Mothe—
Mother, you're here.
My wooden box...
Oh! There it is—
W-What is it?
Are you really dumb or just pretending?
Don't you know what's in it?
What's wrong?
It's just a few books of eroti...
erotic art.
Underneath those books of yours is
the ledger for
the illicit sale of relief grain.
W-What?
Why didn't I know?
No wonder Guo Baofeng was so nervous.
So he passed the hot potato
to me!
You can't even manage a small estate well.
If this thing
falls into Yan Rui's hands,
when implicated,
you'll be beheaded!
Mother,
I'll go beg Lord Wei now.
You...
Why'd you deliver yourself to his door?
Wei Changyan would love nothing more
than for you to die for him now.
Listen carefully.
You can't let anyone know
that this ledger is in our hands.
Also,
if Guo Baofeng asks,
just say
I burned it.
Okay.
Yes, I got it.
Second Madam!
-Second Madam!
-You may leave.
Okay.
-Second Madam.
-Goodness.
What's the panic?
Second Madam,
our estate is
in big trouble!
What could've happened?
Didn't we withhold the tenants' wages?
They heard about our usury business.
Having nowhere else
to turn for their money,
they're now inciting people to riot!
A disaster also hit us this year,
and all the money lent out
can't be recovered.
With all this going on,
things are
going to get real messy.
Everything and everyone is a headache.
Where did those tenants
get such reliable news?
Could someone be
leaking information behind our backs?
I'm also wondering about this.
It wasn't me, Second Madam.
I absolutely did not leak a single word.
Second Madam.
About us moving the money,
only you and I know.
If it wasn't you,
could it have been me?
I'm innocent.
You know that
I guard our estate
like my own life.
Why'd I leak it?
I value my life and this prosperity
too much for that.
Right?
Alright.
I'll figure something out.
You may leave.
She's losing her marbles.
Keep a close eye on her.
Don't let her handle
anything important.
Second Madam,
if this gets out,
we can't keep it under wraps for long.
We need to plan ahead.
Here, Qingyuan.
Thank you, Second Madam.
What's the occasion today?
You actually thought of
inviting Qingyuan for a meal.
Old Madam,
Nanny Rong and I are
getting up there in years.
I fear we may no longer have the stamina
to oversee the estate
day in and day out.
If we don't visit,
we can't keep the subordinates in check.
So after thinking it over,
I thought it'd be better to find someone
from the younger generation
to help me out.
It's so kind of you
to care about this old servant.
With these old bones of mine,
I'm used to working.
If I had nothing to do,
I wouldn't know what to do with myself.
Qingyuan,
you've suffered so much outside
all these years.
Now that you're back in the Xie family,
I must make sure
you're treated with the utmost care.
But you have a strong personality.
You're certainly not one to accept
gifts of gold and jewels.
So I thought I should
hand the estate over
to Qingyuan to manage.
Second Madam.
Do you think I'm cut out for business?
Besides, isn't the estate
usually managed by Second Brother?
If I take it over so abruptly,
it might be inappropriate.
What's inappropriate about it?
Your second brother caused such a big mess
at the government office.
He can't even take care of himself.
How could I leave the estate to him?
You have the skills and the guts.
I'll feel at ease
leaving the estate to you.
Old Madam, what do you think?
Handing over the estate
is no small matter.
Why rush, Second Madam?
Why not wait for the patriarch to return?
It won't be too late to let him decide.
The patriarch has
so many things to deal with.
No need to bother him
with such a small household matter.
But Fourth Lady is
of noble and precious birth.
She probably can't even
tell wheatgrass from chives.
Old Madam, I'm just a foolish servant.
But even in the hardest of times,
the estate's never
let the household go hungry, has it?
Nanny Rong, you're right to criticize me.
I'm not as capable as you.
But I don't know where I heard that
the estate spends
hundreds of taels of silver yearly
to build some canal.
Yet, for some reason,
the tenant farmers there
can't even dig a well.
I wonder where that canal
leads to.
What canal?
There's no such thing.
On the contrary,
why is my bracelet on your wrist?
First Madam, look.
Where's the bracelet?
Preposterous!
First Madam,
my bracelet...
I...
What bracelet?
On my arm,
there are only scars left by you, Nanny.
It hurts to have my scars
on display for everyone.
It's so humiliating.
What a loyal servant you are.
It's not enough that
you took the law into your own hands
and harmed Qingyuan before.
Now you dare to be even more insolent
right in my presence!
Misappropriating funds
and abusing your master!
Confiscate her badge!
The estate will be
handed over to Qingyuan.
She's our own flesh and blood.
No outsider gets to mistreat her.
And you.
Bring such filth near me again,
and you'll be stripped
of your management rights
over this household.
Old Madam, you're right.
You old servant,
how dare you bully Qingyuan?
See how I deal with you.
Chuntai, beat her hard!
I've lost my appetite.
Careful.
Old Madam!
I clearly saw
my bracelet on your arm.
Is this what you're talking about?
You did do it on purpose.
Come with me
to report to Old Madam.
Let's settle this head-on.
Nanny, you must be getting senile.
So what if I did it on purpose?
I'm Old Madam's biological granddaughter.
Settle this head-on?
Do you think
she'll side with a servant like you?
You deliberately set me up.
I've endured for decades
in the Xie Residence.
You, a bastard who came out of nowhere,
have no right to steal the estate from me!
Bastard?
What a familiar title.
Nineteen years ago,
when you beat my mother black and blue
and she begged you for mercy,
you called her that too.
My mother never hurt anyone.
Why did you mistreat her like that?
So you came for revenge.
What does your mother's business
have to do with me?
I was just following my master's orders.
If you're that capable,
go target those high and mighty masters!
How did you know?
That is my plan.
Justice has a long arm.
The evil you committed back then
has finally caught up with you.
What long arm of justice?
Give my bracelet back!
I'm just a servant who climbed the ladder!
Give it back!
If you have the guts, go after them!
Look at yourself.
How pathetic.
You spent your entire life
clawing your way up,
only to become
a mere dog
for a high official's concubine.
[Danyue Pavilion]
My Lady.
The estate Mei Yinghua gave you
is indeed problematic.
They say
the estate has been
using the tenants' money
for usury for years,
delaying the payments owed to tenants.
Now the matter has blown up.
I'm afraid it'll be hard to suppress.
It might reach Old Madam soon.
It's fine.
One step at a time.
I'm already studying
the estate's ledger.
Did you find any clues
in the ledger?
Since she had the nerve to hand it over,
she must've scrubbed it clean.
This ledger shows absolutely nothing.
Only by going to the estate to crosscheck
might I find some holes.
To bring down Nanny Rong,
you took on this hot potato.
That's a massive price to pay.
And look at your body full of wounds.
What kind of heiress
chooses to live like this?
Baoxian,
it's all thanks to you
for swiping that bracelet for me.
Otherwise, I wouldn't have been able to
take over this hot potato so smoothly.
Granny.
My baby!
Come here.
I missed you so much.
Granny.
I brought you a gift.
Why do you always bring me gifts
when you come back?
I don't care about those things.
All I care about is
you coming back early to be with me.
Granny,
now's not the time yet.
But I promise you
I'll be as quick as I can.
As for that money,
just look at it as
holding onto it on my behalf.
Alright!
Just now, I smelled
my favorite pear curd.
You can't eat this.
I saved it for a regular customer.
If you want some,
I'll make it fresh for you
with extra honey.
Granny,
I've only been gone a few days,
and you have a new regular I don't know?
It's that Young Master Yan
from the capital.
He's been coming
to support my business lately.
He's very nice
and has no airs.
A couple of days ago, he even
helped me move flour.
He was worried
I'd fall and sprain something.
Does he come often?
When?
Why didn't I know?
It's quite a coincidence.
You two always arrive one after another.
You leave, and he shows up right after.
What's wrong, Dear?
Why the frown?
Are you still misunderstanding him?
He's really a nice person.
Granny,
the human heart is hard to gauge.
Anyway, don't trust outsiders easily.
Outsiders?
Fourth Lady, your words are
truly heartbreaking.
Yan,
you came at the right time.
Look,
the soup is ready.
This time,
it's perilla, ginger, and jujube soup.
With your condition,
you need to eat more things
that warm the stomach and dispel cold.
Thank you, Granny.
It smells so good.
I'll pour a bowl for you.
Come out with me for a second.
Lord Yan,
I don't know why
you're relentlessly pursuing me.
I've already gotten
the things you wanted for you.
I've also done what you asked me to do.
Why won't you let me go?
Granny doesn't know a thing.
All your schemes to get close to her
are useless.
You won't get anything out of her.
Have you never truly given anyone
your heart?
Is that why you question
the sincerity of others?
I have no ulterior motives
towards Granny Chen.
She just reminds me of
my loved ones who are gone,
so I want to look out for her.
That's all.
I swear every word
I said is true.
♪ Spring comes to the long gate,
green grass sprouts ♪
You'll say anything, won't you?
What do you mean?
I'm completely sincere.
♪ Red plums bear dewdrops,
bright and serene ♪
♪ Year by year, time drifts along ♪
You two are...
♪ Warmth and chill
of mortal meet and part ♪
Granny Chen,
I forgot to tell you that
♪ No need to heed the wind's soft whisper
and ask about your return ♪
Yunya and I survived
ordeals together in the Xie Residence.
Now we've buried the hatchet.
Ordeals?
♪ Wild geese soar through deep clouds,
waiting for the moon to rest ♪
Dear,
did you suffer?
No, I didn't suffer.
Don't listen to his rubbish.
Really, I didn't suffer.
♪ Old memories lie heavy,
haunting every dream ♪
Look,
aren't I perfectly fine?
Don't you lie to me!
I know you have your difficulties,
but the older generation...
♪ Rises and falls take turns ♪
I mean, you're so young.
♪ Phases of the moon,
unplanned to wax and wane ♪
Your happiness and comfort
matter the most.
♪ Count fallen blooms,
yet never count all pains of parting ♪
Don't take everything upon yourself.
That's right, Yunya.
Don't always push yourself so hard.
♪ You, tender yet sharp,
with thorns by your side ♪
Yan.
♪ Like a dim yet blazing candle ♪
Although I don't know who you really are,
but since you have dealings with the Xies,
you must be no ordinary person.
♪ The wind and rain sigh,
the road stretches far ♪
Please take good care
of my little girl.
♪ Blossoms drift with streams,
affections softly stir ♪
What are you saying?
I don't need his care.
♪ Half real, half illusion;
one cup of spring awakes me ♪
Let's go, Granny.
Don't worry, Granny.
I'll take good care of your dear Yunya.
♪ Burned and released,
held by fate's hand ♪
Let's go.
Slow down. Jeez.
[Heng River Ferry Terminal]
Pay up! Pay up!
Listen to me, everyone!
[Xie Estate]
It's been hell for us!
We've weathered storms all year,
just relying on this little harvest
to earn some pennies to survive!
Yes!
As for them,
they claim natural disasters
affected the harvest,
but secretly embezzled our money
[Bountiful Years and Abundant Harvests]
for private usury!
Is there no justice?
There's no justice!
Folks, we must make them pay up!
[Bountiful Years and Abundant Harvests]
We can't let them treat us like fools!
Yes!
Let's smash this place!
Smash it! Smash it!
[Bountiful Years and Abundant Harvests]
[Tea]
What a brilliant move, Your Lordship.
Falsely claiming that
the estate manager's ledger was recovered
and leaking news of the estate's deficit
really added fuel to the fire
for Xie Estate.
Your Lordship,
right after you mentioned the ledger,
Guo Baofeng went to
see Second Young Master.
So the ledger
must be hidden in the Xie Residence.
That's right.
The estate manager is dead,
and the ledger is in Xie Residence.
They can run, but they can't hide.
Our best option is to wait for a chance
to look around the estate.
I really feel sorry for Fourth Lady.
She got caught in the crossfire
for no reason.
I'm afraid this violent spectacle
will reduce her to tears.
Not necessarily.
After all,
she is the lady I chose.
Fourth Lady is here.
She really came.
Pay up! Pay up!
My Lady, it's dangerous here.
If it doesn't work out, let's just leave.
Since we're here,
we can't be afraid.
Isn't that the manager?
Let's go!
Pay up! Pay up!
Pay up!
Everyone!
Silence!
Pay up!
I'm Xie Qingyuan,
the Fourth Lady of the Xie family.
The elders have
put me in charge
of this estate.
Whatever grievances you have,
you can let me know.
I'll do my best to
solve your problems.
Solve our problems?
How will you solve them?
You just want to repudiate the debt!
They took our money,
and now they've got a woman to talk to us!
-Can you hear me out?
-What's there to hear?
Xies are all the same; all scum!
Let's take her to the authorities!
Wait.
Can you...
Can you hear me out first?
What are you doing?
-Let go of My Lady!
-My Lord.
Let go!
Let me go!
Move!
Your Lordship, Fourth Lady is...
That's right.
I am a Xie.
But I didn't grow up in the Xie household.
Since I was little,
I wandered outside alone.
My mother died early,
and I had no one to rely on.
I used to
perform on the streets
and beg for food.
Sometimes,
for a bowl of porridge,
I'd kowtow in front of a porridge stall.
For a steamed bun,
I'd beg over half of Liuzhou.
I've seen countless
ugly faces of the rich.
Your suffering today
was my visceral pain yesterday.
Believe it or not,
I, Xie Qingyuan,
sincerely want to
solve the problems for you.
-Why should I trust you?
-Yeah! Why should I trust you?
Because I know
that for every day this money is delayed,
more people will go hungry.
You can choose not to believe me,
and I cannot represent the Xie family.
But I, Xie Qingyuan, guarantee with my
reputation and conscience
that if the Xie family
doesn't pay back this money,
I, Xie Qingyuan,
will compensate you in full!
My Lady!
Your Lordship.
Bring me your IOUs.
And mine.
-This is mine.
-Here's mine.
This is my IOU.
-Fingerprint mine first!
-Mine!
Excuse me.
Mine! Mine!
Don't push.
Is this real?
My blood
is my seal.
Within 7 days,
with the IOU bearing my fingerprint,
you can ask the estate for money.
If the estate really owes you money,
it'll be repaid threefold,
and your rent will be halved!
Bravo!
She actually managed to put out
the fire I started.
[Bountiful Years and Abundant Harvests]
As I thought, such a situation
doesn't faze you at alll.
Lord Yan, you sure are in high spirits.
When I was in grave danger just now,
you just hid in the back
watching the drama unfold.
You have a sharp mind.
If I intervened rashly,
wouldn't it ruin the good show?
However...
if you fail to keep your promise,
the tenants' backlash
will be beyond disastrous.
How do you know I can't keep my promise?
Then how will you solve it?
Are you curious?
Lord Yan, since you love
watching the drama
and care so much about Xie Estate,
I must take you to see it for yourself.
If I tell you in advance,
it'll ruin the fun, won't it?
[Xie Residence of Hengtang]
Oh, Lord Yan. Stop.
My darling,
how's the task I assigned coming along?
It's been completed, of course.
It's worth everything I've done
to get you the estate.
You have incredible foresight, My Lord.
Second Madam is indeed
behind the private usury.
But the account is in a deficit now.
That's why the tenants
were making a scene.
Years of managing the household have made
Concubine Mei very resourceful.
Even if we get evidence,
she'll never admit it.
She'll just have someone take the blame.
That's of course.
Second Madam is behind the scenes.
Nanny Rong is the one
who actually handles everything.
When Nanny Rong
is arrested...
Did I hear something?
Maybe it's a stray cat.
You sure know how to joke.
When Nanny Rong
is arrested and executed,
the truth will be buried.
By then,
Concubine Mei's name will be cleared.
You'll also have unearthed the truth
and can answer to Old Madam.
Yes.
She's just a mere nanny.
Who will care if she dies?
So Second Madam put Nanny Rong in charge
just to leave herself a way out.
Then you should get ready
to report to Old Madam tomorrow.
MkvDrama.net